{"tossups": [{"question": "Donald Graves argued that an officer lacking experience in this battle failed to use skirmish pickets to protect his soon-to-be-stolen guns. In this battle, James Miller responded, \u201cI\u2019ll try, Sir\u201d when told to capture enemy guns. Phineas Riall was captured in this battle which preceded an engagement at Chippawa. Jacob Brown was wounded in this battle after which the Americans retreated to Fort Erie. For the point, name this 1814 battle on the Ontario side of Niagara Falls, a strategic victory for the British in which Winfield Scott was wounded.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Lundy\u2019s Lane</b> (accept Battle of<b> Niagara Falls</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In repainting an image commissioned by the DAR of a 1777 battle, this artist omitted an anachronistic obelisk. Works by this painter were displayed at Gimbel\u2019s Department store with the help of Otto Kallir, who oversaw production of Christmas cards featuring this artist\u2019s works before<em> Hallmark</em>. This resident of Eagle Bridge, New York created flattened, idyllic scenes of rural life such as<em> Sugaring Off</em>. A museum in Bennington, Vermont boasts the largest collection of works by, for the point, what appropriately-nicknamed elderly female painter?", "answer": "<b> Grandma Moses</b> (accept Anna Mary Robertson<b> Moses</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This region was home to the Kerma Culture that absorbed the Sai people but disappeared by 1500 BC. The queen mothers of this kingdom were known as the Kandake, the greatest of whom was Queen Amanirenas. After being defeated by Psamettichus II, this kingdom relocated its capital from Napata to Apedemak. In Egyptian writings, this kingdom was referred to as Medjay, but unlike Egypt, this kingdom\u2019s pyramids have a very steep angle. For the point, name this Nubian kingdom, located in what is today southern Egypt and norther Sudan.", "answer": "<b> Kush</b> (prompt on \u201cNubia\u201d or \u201cSudan\u201d before \u201ckingdom\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "After being appointed by this leader, Antipope Philip served for one day and then disappeared. This man\u2019s son, Adelgis, attempted to restore this man\u2019s kingdom but was defeated in Calabria. This man was exiled to Corbie Abbey in Picardy after being besieged at his capital of Ticinum, today known as Pavia. This leader\u2019s people were profiled by his rival\u2019s courtier, Paul the Deacon, who sought the hand of this man\u2019s daughter for his Lord. For the point, name this last king of the Lombards who married his daughter off to Charlemagne.", "answer": "<b> Desiderius</b> (accept<b> Daufer</b>ius) Page 1", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "While staying in Nova Scotia, this person helped rescue the survivors of a shipwreck at Sable Island. In a report to the New Jersey legislature in 1845, this person pointed out the condition of a feeble former judge the legislators used to know as an example of the plight of those like him. This woman served as the Superintendent of Union Army nurses during the Civil War, though she is more famous for inspiring the creation of institutions such as Harrisburg State Hospital. For the point, name this American reformer who improved the conditions of mental asylums.", "answer": "Dorothea<b> Dix</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this Russian poet of \u201cBabi Yar.\u201d", "answer": "Yevgeny<b> Yevtushenko</b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "This leader declared \u201cany stigma and disgrace should forever be removed from the names of [Sacco and Vanzetti].\u201d This leader failed in his promise to dismantle the Metropolitan District Commission, which led to a primary loss to Edward J. King. This leader stoically declined to support the death penalty for a hypothetical murderer of his wife at a debate. This Massachusetts governor was attacked for being soft on crime in the Willie Horton ads. For the point, name this Democrat who lost the 1988 U.S. presidential election to George H. W. Bush.", "answer": "Michael<b> Dukakis</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man ordered the Jujuy Exodus and helped propose the Inca Plan to the Congress of Tucum\u00b4an. A ship named for this man was known as the USS<em> Phoenix</em> and became the second ship after the INS <em>Khukri</em> to be sunk by submarine after World War Two.<em> The Sun</em> carried the headline, \u201cGotcha,\u201d after a ship named for this man was sunk, and later editions of the paper carried the line, \u201cDid 1,200 Argies drown?\u201d For the point, name this man who designed the flag of Argentina and also names a ship sunk in the Falklands War.", "answer": "Manuel<b> Belgrano</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this last president of Czechoslovakia and first of the Czech Republic.", "answer": "V\u00b4aclav<b> Havel</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During the Fundamentalist-Modernist Controversy, this lawyer defended Harry Fosdick. This man analyzed the effects of containment in<em> War or Peace</em>. At the Geneva Conference, this diplomat did not recognize the Chinese delegation and refused to shake the hand of Zhou Enlai. This man lobbied for a coup to elevate Carlos Castillo Armas. That coup, known as Operation PBSUCCESS, overthrew Jacobo\u00b4Arbenz and was backed by the United Fruit Company. For the point, name this Secretary of State under Eisenhower whose brother Allen led the CIA.", "answer": "<b> J</b>ohn Foster<b> Dulles</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The title of these people comes from an Old French word meaning \u201cdunce\u201d or \u201csimpleton.\u201d These people supported the future king Louis VIII, but the defeat of the French fleet at Dover and the capture of Robert Fitzwalter ended a war named after these people. Simon de Montfort briefly ruled England as a leader of these people, but his defeat to Edward I at Evesham ended the second war named for these people. For the point, name these landowners who forced King John to grant them more rights in the Magna Carta.", "answer": "English<b> baron</b>s (prompt on \u201cnobles,\u201d \u201clandowners,\u201d or equivalents)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A banner reading \u201cRoll Up - No Chinese\u201d was displayed during this country\u2019s violent anti-Chinese Lambing Flat Riots. Philip Cunningham stated, \u201cDeath or Liberty\u201d during a rebellion in this country that included fighting in the Second Battle of Vinegar Hill. Lachlan Macquarie became governor of a state in this country following a rebellion led by George Johnson and John Macarthur. The Castle Hill Uprising occurred in, for the point, what country, whose Rum Rebellion deposed William Bligh as governor of New South Wales?", "answer": "Commonwealth of<b> Australia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Before this agreement, Konrad Henlein put forth the Karlsbader Programm. Due to one side\u2019s actions before this agreement, that country\u2019s own counter-espionage agency tried to overthrow it in the Oster Conspiracy. Even though this agreement concerned their lands, President Edvard Benes of Czechoslovakia was not invited. After this agreement was signed, Neville Chamberlain claimed that this was a \u201cpeace for our time.\u201d For the point, name this piece of appeasement legislation that gave Nazi Germany the Sudetenland.", "answer": "<b> Munich Agreement</b> (accept<b> Munich Betrayal</b>) Page 6", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Name this man, voted the \u201cGreatest Frenchman of All Time\u201d by France 2 viewers in 2005.", "answer": "Charles<b> de Gaulle</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "The Supreme Court ruled that Wisconsin could not nullify a part of this bill in<em> Ableman v. Booth</em>. In anticipation of this bill\u2019s consequences, the Nashville Convention was held. Senator William Seward argued against this bill on the basis of a \u201chigher law than the Constitution.\u201d This agreement, supported by President Fillmore and brokered by Stephen Douglas and Henry Clay, admitted California to the Union in exchange for revision to the Fugitive Slave Act. For the point, name this successor to the Missouri Compromise that postponed secession.", "answer": "Compromise of<b> 1850</b> (anti-prompt on \u201cFugitive Slave Act\u201d or \u201cFugitive Slave Law\u201d before\u201cadmitted\u201d) Page 7", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A leader of these people was strangled by a cow hide thong after failing to defeat Mpande, the half-brother of the king, at the Battle of Maqongqo. These people were able to establish an empire during a period known as \u201cThe Crushing.\u201d In 1837, King Dingane killed Piet Retief and 500 others in the Weenen Massacre. In one conflict, the capital of these people, Ulundi, was burned down but not before they managed to win the Battle of Isandlwana against Lord Chelmsford\u2019s British regulars. For the point, name these South African people led by Shaka.", "answer": "<b> Zulu</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}